<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Rich Insights</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>A Follow-up to Questions on Physics</title><link href="/a-follow-up-to-questions-on-physics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Rich James</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-20:/a-follow-up-to-questions-on-physics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Getting answers to my questions (most of them, anyway)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last blog, I discussed reading Richard Feynman's Six Easy Pieces and questions I had after reading partly through his chapter on Quantum Behavior. Not surprisingly, some of these were answered if only I had finished reading the chapter before posting that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Getting answers to my questions (most of them, anyway)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last blog, I discussed reading Richard Feynman's Six Easy Pieces and questions I had after reading partly through his chapter on Quantum Behavior. Not surprisingly, some of these were answered if only I had finished reading the chapter before posting that blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, he acknowledges that light could influence the results of the experiment.  In fact, he talks for a while about possible scenarios to try to reduce that impact.  It turns out that using any light at all will impact the experiment, since light comes in packets (photons) and dimming light doesn't reduce the size or energy of photons, but rather the frequency at which they are emitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He goes on to talk about scenarios where reducing or increasing the wavelength of the light might reduce the impact.  But this leads to the Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle.  Essentially, to eliminate (or sufficiently reduce the impact of the light) so that it doesn't impact the electron's path requires using light at long wavelengths.  And the problem with that is when you use long wavelengths, you can no longer distinguish which slit the electrons go through.  Effectively, the resolution is too blurry to tell what is going on.  As soon as you shorten the wavelength enough to be able to tell what is going on, the light will impact the electron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the slits in the experiment need to be relatively close to one another before you will see the interference pattern in the first place. And that puts a constraint on how you can view things without impacting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to my other question, Feynman didn't address the one on whether you could shoot an electron at a single slit and know it went through that slit. But I did some further digging and it looks like it would not be possible.  Electrons should not be thought of as a single "bullet" but rather as a cloud.  And the size of this cloud is larger than the max distance you can put the two slits and still see the interference pattern.  In a sense, an electron is "bigger" that the distance between the slits, although it will (presumably) pass through only one or the other slit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say "presumably" because it isn't clear what an electron as a cloud really means.  Is the cloud just a probability distribution of where the electron is at any given moment?  That would make it a particle ("bullet") but not one we can pin down.  Or is it some form of shapeless energy -- or maybe not shapeless, but energy in the form of a cloud?  Experiments seem to identify when an electron passes through one slit or the other, even if they do interfere with the electron's path.  I assume they have done those experiments where they fire a single electron and do observe it going only through one slit or the other and never both.  If that is true, then it seems it is the case that a single electron does pass through only one slit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think I have my major questions answered at this point.  I will say that Feynman did a great job of explaining the Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle to me.  I have heard of it before, but I never really had a good understanding of it.  Or I should say, I was not happy with my understanding of it.  Feynman says that, generally, the principle is a statement about the limitations on observing effects without affecting the outcomes.  I have seen it stated elsewhere in a much stronger form that things are in two (or more) places at once and only "collapse" into a single place when observed.  I've never liked that concept.  I think it is better to say that the probability that something is in one place or the other is X% (thus it COULD be in any of these places), but upon observation, doubt is removed as we verify that it is in fact in a single location.  Observation didn't cause it to be in one spot or the other, it simply removed the uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, observation (at least at the atomic scale) also influences the behavior of the things being observed.  To observe something is to change the system. It isn't possible to observe remotely, impartially, as an outside agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next on my list is to learn the basics of quantum computing.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Improving American Football</title><link href="/improving-american-football.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Rich James</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-20:/improving-american-football.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;American football has problems and needs help&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up watching American football (hence forth, "football") starting in the 70's and still do to this day.  Like so many others, I cared very much about the games, who won, who would make the playoffs, who would win the Super Bowl …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;American football has problems and needs help&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up watching American football (hence forth, "football") starting in the 70's and still do to this day.  Like so many others, I cared very much about the games, who won, who would make the playoffs, who would win the Super Bowl.  I became a Dallas Cowboys fan after initially being a Baltimore Colts fan.  My dad had a first cousin who played wide receiver for the Colts back when Johnny Unitas was their quarterback, so naturally I was a fan.  But I switched allegiance to the Cowboys in the mid-70's for the simple reason that they were a good team and both my dad and brother liked them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I enjoyed many years backing a really good team.  Of course, in more recent years, the Cowboys have struggled, but I have stayed a fan of the team.  I keep hoping they will return to greatness and become the dominant team they once were.  I know that the league deliberately structured things to bring parity into the league and I agree with that.  And it has had its intended affect for the most part.  We do still have the New England Patriots, who seem to defy all adversities and stay a strong contender every year.  I chaulk that up to them being an extremely well run organization with an outstanding coach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, I also have thought for a number of years now that football is flawed and only getting worse.  The sport has a vast number of rules and each year, the rules committee tinkers with the rules, changing some that had existed and adding more.  But it has gotten so bad that it is hard to see how players, much less the fans, can know all the rules.  The game has become a microcosm of the American legal morrass. You need a lawyer to navigate our legal system and you need 7 referees (on the field) and at least 2 more off field to control an NFL game.  You also need video replay in order to parse the minutia of events that occur on the field in order to apply highly detailed rules.  And we still are not always sure how to interpet these rules, thus the TV commentators usually have on hand an NFL rules executive to weigh in with an opinion on whether the game officials are making the right call or not.  It's an unwieldly mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of this has happened so that the NFL game can be made more attractive to TV audiences.  Many rules protect receivers and quarterbacks, making spectacular pass plays more likely to happen.  Some of the more recent rules have been created in an attempt to improve player safety, which is understandable.  But I think they are going about it all wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My philosophy regarding sports is that a sport is best if it is reduced to its essential elements, with minimal rules that leave the rest to the actual players.  I like soccer very much.  One reason I find it attractive is that it is a far simpler game than football.  You line up 11 players on each side of a field, define two goals, give them a ball, tell them they may not use their hands, and that the object of the game is to get the ball in the opponent's goal.  That is pretty much it.  Of course, soccer has more rules than that.  Some, I would do away with (the offside rule, for example).  But the rules are really pretty minimal.  There are rules that enforce that you must play the ball, not make deliberate contact with the opponent.  In my philosophy, you could argue that it should be anything goes:  just find a way to get the ball intothe opponent's goal.  It would likely make scoring goals in a modern goal almost impossible, so you might have to change the game to say just get the ball across the opponent's end line, for example.  But I really like the idea of making it a very simple game with very few rules and just let the players play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So back to football.  They have rules to protect quarterbacks now, almost from even breathing on them.  I would eliminate these rules.  Teams will have to find bigger, stronger quarterbacks that can stand back there and perform under duress.  They may have to field multiple quarterbacks rather than depending on a single, highly specialized one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have rules to protect players.  No spearing, no launching oneself like a missle at an opponent, and so on.  I would eliminate helmets and pads from the game.  Even with those protections, players get hurt.  Often, they suffer season ending injuries.  But because they wear helmets and pads, they also have incentives to attempt more dangerous play.  I doubt anyone would launch themselves headfirst into an opponent if they were not wearing helmets and pads.  There are rugby leagues in North America and Europe.  Those players wear minimal pads.  No facemasks, helmets that mostly protect ears, and little if any other padding.  Yes, they get hurt.  But not inordinately so.  The players play differently when they have less padding.  I think NFL players would do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be more honest to make these changes.  Football is a gladiator sport.  People watch it for the physical violence it presents.  They admire the skill of good players too.  Great running backs that juke and move to make the defenders miss their tackles are impressive.  I realize, however, that these changes would likely severely change the passing game.  I would consider eliminating pass interference.  The rule should be: when the ball is in the air it is a free-for-all for anyone to gain possession.  No one has an innate right to catch it.  Blocking is already allowed in football and that means physically impairing the other player from moving where he wants to move.  I see no reason why this shouldn't apply to trying to catch a ball.  In fact, in football, if the ball is tipped by the defense on its way to its intended target, you can knock each other down in an attempt to catch the ball.  I see no need for a special rule that says when you can do this and when you can't.  The principle should just be: if the ball is loose (i.e. not in a player's possession), it is a free-for-all and anyone can get the ball and knock or block other players attempting to get the ball.  Consider that with these changes, new types of plays would be developed.  It would be legal to pick a defender anywhere on the field to free up a receiver.  Defenses would have to adapt to that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further simplify the game, they should eliminate the eligible receiver rule.  Anyone is eligible to catch the ball.  That would blow the game wide open and compensate for the difficulty in getting a man free.  It would also put teams to a test: do we put a bunch of good hands guys on the line of scrimmage or do we emphasize using big guys to block and protect the quarterback and open lanes for the running back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren't an exhaustive list of changes that should be made, but they do illustrate the concept of simplifying the sport by eliminating rules and equipment to help render to a more primal, natural basis.  The sport today has become a big turn off to me.  I actually don't enjoy watching the game much anymore.  I still do, mostly out of habit (and hope that it will improve), but I often just don't even tune in these days.  While I know none of these ideas will ever be adopted, it's still fun to think about and dream of what could be.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Six Easy Pieces - Ruminating on Quantum Behavior</title><link href="/six-easy-pieces-ruminating-on-quantum-behavior.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Rich James</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-18:/six-easy-pieces-ruminating-on-quantum-behavior.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;An amateur's thougths and questions over a foundational physics experiment.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading Richard Feynman's Six Easy Pieces and am currently working my way through the 6th chapter, Quantum Behavior.  I am not new to these ideas, but was and still am excited to hear Mr. Feynman's explanation of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;An amateur's thougths and questions over a foundational physics experiment.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been reading Richard Feynman's Six Easy Pieces and am currently working my way through the 6th chapter, Quantum Behavior.  I am not new to these ideas, but was and still am excited to hear Mr. Feynman's explanation of quantum behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, he describes the classic double slit experiment, which appears to reveal that electrons behave both like particles and like waves.I probably should wait until I have completed reading this chapter, but I have questions right now that I want to write down in case he doesn't address them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that I don't think they have been addressed already by the scientific community.  I hope I can find out more about that.  I would love to see the answers.  But what are these questions I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, first he describes how if you put a detector on the back wall, behind the slits, you can count the electrons that hit the detector in the spot where it is located.  He describes moving the detector back and forth so that you can count the electrons that hit the back wall at various points on it.  Perhaps he has simplified the explanation so much that he omits that the actual experiments have many detectors on the back wall?  I don't know, but I would like to know if that is how they have been done.  In particular, in his explanation of how the results change when they try to detect when electrons go through hole 1 vs hole 2, I am curious what would happen if many detectors were set up.  What I fundamentally am trying to know is if they can measure WHAT hits the back wall whenever they measure an electron going through hole 1 or hole 2.  Is it possible to record, say, 2 hits when it goes through one hole or the other?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I'd like to know the results they get when firing electrons slowly, one at a time.  Very slowly.  Both when the experiment is set up to measure which hole they go through and when it is set up to not measure which hole.  Supposedly, when we are not measuring, the probability of where the electron will hit the back wall conforms to the wave probability.  But have they conclusively proven that only a single electron is fired and still exhibits this interference pattern?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, it seems they are saying that electrons "hit" the detector as a single unit, as if hitting it with just the one electron.  But it's probability for where it will hit when two holes are available varies depending on if we try to measure which hole it actually goes through.  I'm not denying the results, but am curious if the conclusion is actually that a single electron exhibits interference patterns with itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, regarding measuring the electrons to see which hole they pass through.  It seems to me that using light, or any form of energy for that matter, has the potential to interfere with the experiment.  By triggering a light when passing near it, does that not interfere with the electron's path?  I've often wondered if a photon of light could change the energy state or otherwise interfere with the behavior of atomic and subatomic particles.  I'm not sure how else you could detect which hole an electron goes through though.  Could you not set up an experiment that was calibrated to shoot single electrons through hole 1 in a 2 hole experiment, then measure the distribution at the back wall?  Measuring where the electron arrives seems cleaner to me, since that is the endpoint of its path.  It might still be possibly true that measuring it even there could somehow impact whether it arrives there though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as I stated before, I expect all of these questions have been asked before and are already answered.  What I really want is to find explanations of those experiments.  I'll do some digging after I finish this book.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Golf is Sublime. Golf Sucks.</title><link href="/golf-is-sublime-golf-sucks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Rich James</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-11:/golf-is-sublime-golf-sucks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Golf is a tease.  It is fickle.  It will mesmerize you.  It will tear your heart out.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have worked quite a lot at become a decent golfer.  Not that I get to play much. In fact, I hardly play at all -- maybe twice or three times in a year …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Golf is a tease.  It is fickle.  It will mesmerize you.  It will tear your heart out.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have worked quite a lot at become a decent golfer.  Not that I get to play much. In fact, I hardly play at all -- maybe twice or three times in a year.  That doesn't count chip and pitch par 3 courses.  But I have spent massive time watching golf videos on youtube, working on my mechanics in my living room and out at the range.  And I have developed a pretty good swing as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have certain swing flaws that aggravate me.  They aren't unique to me.  Most amateur golfers struggle with these things.  I sometimes hit it fat (i.e. chunk the ball, i.e. hit the ground behind the ball).  Some days I hit it quite straight.  Others, I push to the right or pull to the left.  I can hit nice high iron shots, but they don't go as far as I think they should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in my searching around and from discussing these things with my dad and brother, I stumbled upon Rotary Swing Golf.  This is yet another golf instructor online who will sell you his system and you get access to hundreds of videos explaining and teaching how to swing the club better.  Now while there are plenty of these guys out there and I, being a very skeptical sort of guy, normally will not buy what they are selling, in this case I did just that.  I did that because the concepts I saw Chuck (the founder) talking about in his free videos resonated strongly with me.  They made great sense.  He breaks the swing down into comprehensible parts and explains the why, including the body mechanics.  Anyhow, he spoke to me, so I bought his system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I am a huge fan.  He has helped me hit the ball more consistently and farther than I ever have.  I now rarely hit a fat shot.  My distance is better.  My new swing flaw, when I have one, is to hook it left.  But everything I have been doing now is quite playable.  I could take this to the course and actually feel like I am a decent golfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, except when it all comes crashing down, which is just what it did over the past 3 days.  I was at the cusp of hitting the best shots of my life.  I had learned to keep my wrists and forearms relaxed and allow the downswing to actually increase lag, which I then would release at impact.  This was producing really nice, long shots with relatively little effort.  But, toward the end of a large bucket of balls last Friday, I suddenly started hitting shanks. Basically, hitting the ball off the heel or even the heel/shaft part of the club.  The ball would shoot off right in an extreme slice with little or no air.  I tried to fix this, but was not able to get rid of it.  Sure, some hits would still be good ones, but those shanks would rear right back up.  That meant there was no consistency anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chaulked it up to fatique after hitting a large bucket and went home.  I wasn't mad.  Frustrated a bit, yes.  But mostly puzzled over why I started hitting those and what was it I was doing to cause it.  My brother and I had plans to play a round of golf (yay!) at his club on the following Tuesday.  I was really looking forward to that.  So I knew I needed to get back out and regroove my swing before we got out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on Monday, I headed back out, got a medium bucket of balls and got to work.  And, crap, right off -- still the shanks.  Really ugly, ugly shots and contact.  I stayed calm and focused on fundamentals.  I tried to use the 9 to 3 drill to get back the feel of correct contact with the ball.  That drill has never been real good for me and it wasn't then either.  I tried all kinds of things, but over the entire medium bucket, I hit maybe 85% shanks/crap shots.  I looked and felt like a rank beginner.  Yes, some shots were decent contact.  They always went high and straight left.  So, basically, a pull left.  Not a hook.  While it was nice to hit some into the air, even that was not playable.  I needed to be able to hit where I was aiming, not 20-30 yards left of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back to the shack and got another, small bucket so I could keep working out the issues.  Well, no need to belabor this sad story any longer.  I didn't work it out.  I left that day with a million questions in my mind, trying to sort out what the heck I had started doing so wrong.  With that small bucket, I got out my phone and recorded me hitting balls from both the face-on view and the down-the-line view.  At least I had that to look at when I got home so I could maybe figure out what I was doing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had to cancel the golf outing with my brother.  Such a bummer! And this is why I say golf tears your heart out.  I don't get to play much in the first place. And I don't get to see my brother as often as I like either.  And I was primed, really hitting the ball extremely well right as we were about to go out and play 18 holes.  And then golf says, "Nope! I'm taking it all back!  You suck and have no business being out there.  You have much work still to do."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I'll do that work.  I'm sorting through the issues as we speak. Video review seems to show I have started pushing with my right leg on the downswing.  I've become too right-sided again.  This is probably from me getting sloppy and trying to add more power to my swing to get better distance.  At least, this is one of my theories.  What I need to work on is the core fundamental of the lower body rotating first, getting the shoulders to be square or even slightly close at impact, keeping my posture and fully releasing the club.  And I really do need to focus on closing the clubface at least some when on the downswing.  I need those left hand nuckles to roll downward as I swing through the impact area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it's a sad story.  It's my sad story.  It isn't truly important.  This is golf after all, just hitting a little ball into a hole.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except, it's so much more than that.  It's about personal performamce.  Executing a skill that requires physical coordination, timing, finesse and power.  It also requires judgement, at least when actually playing.  Not every swing is a full swing.  Not every lie is a flat lie on fairway grass.  And, all else aside, when you hit a ball pure, in the sweet spot, the way it is supposed to be hit, it feels magical.  And you want to do that again and again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I will.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>First Post on My Sweet New Blog</title><link href="/first-post-on-my-sweet-new-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Rich James</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-06:/first-post-on-my-sweet-new-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;I am On My Way To Internet Fame and Fortune!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my new blog.  While not super informative, it should convey my sense of excitement and eagerness to engage with you, the reader!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;I am On My Way To Internet Fame and Fortune!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my new blog.  While not super informative, it should convey my sense of excitement and eagerness to engage with you, the reader!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>From COBOL to Aprons</title><link href="/from-cobol-to-aprons.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Rich James</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-06:/from-cobol-to-aprons.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Finding the New Me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been a technology guy in one way or another for over 30 years.  I started out as a programmer, coding first in COBOL, then C and C++.  I moved on to project management when I showed, apparently, enough maturity and doggedness that I could be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Finding the New Me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been a technology guy in one way or another for over 30 years.  I started out as a programmer, coding first in COBOL, then C and C++.  I moved on to project management when I showed, apparently, enough maturity and doggedness that I could be trusted to run an entire project.  And that was a web app, something very new to me at the time.  I continued managing various iterations of a major web app for a large accounting firm until I finally moved on to something with even bigger responsibilities: "product management".  Actually, this was more like product portfolio management and I had the job of keeping a suite of applications, and their users, happy, productive and cost effective.  In time, this grew into an even bigger role where I was managing a team of about 15 people who each managed parts of a very large product portfolio for two major business areas of that accounting firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as things go at said accounting firm, every 2-3 years, they do a reorg.  This is typically the result of shuffling the senior leadership so that partners get chances to burnish their resumes, careers and bank accounts via highly visible primo roles.  And each time this shuffle occurs, well, partners must make their mark.  For the CTO, the usual easiest way to do that is to reorganize the IT function, shaving people in the process to produce the cost savings the CTO promised/was charged with to help maximize that ROI for the partners.  I survived many iterations of this process until I finally didn't.  They let me go 2 years ago, proving to this rather dense tech guy that loyalty and hard work really do not mean much in terms of job security.  And I didn't just work hard and sing the party line, I was good at what I did.  They told me this every year and paid me bonuses to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I emerged from this with a very sour taste in my mouth for "working for the man." I didn't like that others could control my future like that and wanted to become my own boss.  And this brings me to: aprons.  You see, I decided I wanted to start and run a business.  And I decided the best way to do that would be to sell retail products on Amazon, at least at first.  There are many benefits to using Amazon in this way, mainly in them handling inventory, shipping, payments and hosting.  This left me with the minor problems of finding something that people might want to buy, get it made at a reasonable cost, get it delivered to Amazon, create a decent product page to showcase my product and advertise the daylights out of it so people would know about it.  Oh, and make a profit while doing all that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, I concluded that aprons would be a thing worth trying.  I looked at lots of product ideas before settling on aprons.  I used tools to help me research products, the demand for such, how crowded the market was for things, etc. and concluded that bib aprons would be my first product.  My idea was to make a really good apron and initially thought I'd sell it for a modest $15 or so.  But one of the samples from a manufacturer, was of a black pinstripe denim material.  I thought it looked very classy and so settled on it.  I also decided the price could be higher to match that classier look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I could go on in gory detail about my experiences thus far in retail.  But the real reason I even brought it up is to point out that I had to learn completely new skills to do any of this.  Stuff that was utterly alien to my tech-heavy background.  I had to form a legal company.  I opened a business bank account.  I did product research.  I solicted bids from manufacturers, negotiated with them and reached agreement, through contract, with one to be my supplier.  I hired a freight forwarder company to manage the shipping process from the manufacturer to Amazon.  I built a home photography studio and created my own pictures for my listing.  I learned new software tools to enable this proccess: darktable, inkscape, gimp. I learned how to do tethered photography, which makes it so much easier to adjust your shots while in the studio.  I've learned and am still learning about advertising and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an old dog who has learned new tricks.  I have no particular deep love for aprons.  They chose me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know where all of this will take me.  It has been an emotional rollercoaster.  I am challenged every day with self-doubt and imposter syndrome.  But I push that aside and press on.  And I have not let any of that stop me from moving forward.  I am my own boss.  I own it.  I sink or swim with it.  It is scary, scary, scary.  But exciting too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, if you want to see my apron, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07MFFYXWS"&gt;here's the link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Running a Blog on Github with Python and virtual environments</title><link href="/running-a-blog-on-github-with-python-and-virtual-environments.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Rich James</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-06-06:/running-a-blog-on-github-with-python-and-virtual-environments.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;How I modified the opensource.com article so I could use a virtual python environment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog exists because of this article:  &lt;a href="https://opensource.com/article/19/5/run-your-blog-github-pages-python?utm_medium=Email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=weekly&amp;amp;sc_cid=701f20000012r6qAAA"&gt;Run your blog on GitHub Pages with Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I ran into some issues when trying to follow the directions in that article.  It turns out, they were …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;How I modified the opensource.com article so I could use a virtual python environment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog exists because of this article:  &lt;a href="https://opensource.com/article/19/5/run-your-blog-github-pages-python?utm_medium=Email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=weekly&amp;amp;sc_cid=701f20000012r6qAAA"&gt;Run your blog on GitHub Pages with Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I ran into some issues when trying to follow the directions in that article.  It turns out, they were due to me wanting to create an isolated python environment, which is good practice, when following those instructions.  I created a new virtual environment in which to try the things in that article.  But, I ran into some issues coordinating between github and my environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, these are the steps I followed to successfully create this blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new github repository as instructed (username/username.github.io)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone that repository onto my local machine and call it 'blog'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mkvirtualenv -a . -p python3.6 blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pip install pelican ghp-import Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git checkout -b content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pelican-quickstart (and fill out as instructed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git add .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git commit -m 'initial pelican commit to content'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git push origin content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd content/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mkdir pages images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cp /home/rich/Pictures/me.jpg images/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;touch first-post.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;touch pages/about.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vim first-post.md (and add whatever text into this file)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vim pages/about.md (and add whatever text into this file)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd ..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pelican content -o output -s publishconf.py&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ghp-import -m "Generate Pelican site" --no-jekyll -b master output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git push origin master&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git add content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git commit -m 'added a first post, a photo and an about page'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git push origin content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I have the blog set up with the first page and the about page, all updated at github. I can view my blog at &lt;a href="https://richjames.github.io/category/misc.html"&gt;https://richjames.github.io/category/misc.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use virtualenvwrapper to manage python environments, which can be seen at step 4 above.  When I am done working in such an environment, just enter 'deactivate' to end the environment session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create more content, this is the workflow (assuming you have not started the virtual environment yet):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workon blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd content/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;touch second-post.md  (example name here.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vim second-post.md (add content)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd ..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pelican content -o output -s publishconf.py&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ghp-import -m "Generate Pelican site" --no-jekyll -b master output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git push origin master&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git add content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git commit -m 'added a first post, a photo and an about page'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git push origin content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deactivate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the workflow here could be simplified with some scripts, but I just created all this, so that is a refinement for later. I'll provide an update later when I do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>